Well, my friends and welcome to exercise number one hundred and five in this exercise, we are going
to create the Ford Fulkerson algorithm in Jaffa, so I would go to the algorithm package and they will
call it Ford cars.
And you can download all of these source codes from that resource folder under each exercise on our
to do so.
Oops.
This is Ford Focus.
Now
we start by creating here aesthetic fine and v be equal to six.
Then using the binary that breadth first search using the F s as the search algorithm
Boolean public
boolean.
Be as.
Please go back to the BFC breadth first search algorithm in searching algorithms section.
And to learn more about the famous graph it scrappers to era and ask us which is the state, if their
source and the destination points
from where to where we need to move and we get the maximum flow.
So Boolean visit is
equal to a new Boolean
but index fee, no form of lengthy and I equal to zero I less than being a plus plus.
All right.
What we need to do.
We make visited Index II equal to 12, so we make it false.
We have created an array visited and we initialize it.
All of it is equal to false or elements of this array.
We need to insulate them to force.
Now we start by making a link, at least implementing that as linkages from Java tutorial package and
link.
At least it took into their Typekit to meet their integer.
And I will name it as Q, you remember the Q?
Yes.
So please go back in there to the previous exercise and it is in order to learn about the link at list
and that Q Q Dot and S.
And if that and S s equal to true, then be at index s
equal to minus one, while Q the size does not equal to zero, then what we will do, we initialize
into equal two Q Dot Ball No.
Four Int V equal to zero v less than the capital v the vertices.
And so we have all the vertices.
So.
We check if it is visited and visited at Index B, equal equal to falls, so if there's not visited
here and so we have any Boolean expressions here, graph at index at Index U and the Index V greater
than zero, then what we need to make, we need to add them to the queue.
So we see guys that we have to check this is that equal to false, so it is not visited.
And here is.
And so this condition should be true and this condition should be true and the same condition.
We are checking that the graph index u and this fee is greater than zero p at Index B, B at index fee
so equal to you and visited at Index V.
Let me make it pass through because we have already visit.
Now let's return here.
The visited visited at index, the index, the equal equal to false if the equal to true.
OK, now.
We need to apply the Ford Focus, an algorithm.
We start by creating public for first person.
And like, I will create it as.
I'll go.
Ordered not to to confuse with that constructor.
So and craft took that parameter to add to the array and asks that starting point and that indeed that
finishing
we start by making here.
This is meant to cause a return and therefore low the maximum flow, so into you and into the end a
graph here we make it as to the array equal to new and at index, the index length the length.
So for you equal to zero you less than v you plus plus we make another nested loops.
So four v equal to zero v less than the capital and V Plus plus we start assigning the graph at index
the U V
equal to the graph that we have created Appendix Q and Index V.
Now, so we create an Int B for their predecessors, equal to you and at length B
and end max flow equal to zero.
Now we start updating the residual.
Goals of updating their residual values of at wide B.F., as we are using the PAFs breadth first search
past the graph first as best they and best be, though the variables that we have created before and
path of flow, we need to calculate the flow so it is equal to integer.
The maximum value for four v equal to T V does not equal to S and V equal with the equal to be at Index
V..
OK, so you are equal to P at Index V at best flow equal to math.
Dot find the minimum between the best flow and the graph at Index U and V.
OK.
So this is for the for loop inside the wire loop.
Another for loop, we will make it V equal to T v.
That's not equal to S and V equal to be at index of B B at Index B.
OK, so this is the that loop that we are going to go through you equal to be at Index V.
We put the U at that graph at index u v equal do the old graph u v minus the path flow so far that I
will make a shortcut that flow.
We are subtracting the best flow from it and in the same way I will put here v u because the index here,
we're going to need to update it.
But here is the plus.
The Earth flow now
here is there and adding the path flows max flow plus equals death flow.
OK, so
very max flow.
Now, let's test our approach public static void, main stream
arcs,
and we pass here that graph that we are going to create.
So Intergraph, that I will make a matrix here called Graph.
So I post the video and I will create.
So this is that our graph that we are creating and we need to apply the Ford Focus on it to see the
maximum flow.
So Ford Focus and Ford Focus, and this is an object from the class the we are creating.
The new Ford Focus.
And we start by creating and calculate the maximum flow by calling here,
the maximum flow is equal to four for the board, Ford Focus and the Ford Focus, an algorithm with
best graph that that we have created.
We need to start from zero and we need to reach five.
OK.
So as is equal to zero and five is let's run and.
The maximum flow is six, and this is correct, because if you throw this would be a free trial, drove
this graph and you will see that the maximum flow between these weighted objects, these points and
corresponding weights and that flow the maximum flow would be six.
So four focus and applications are on their water distribution pipelines, bipartite matching problem
and circulation with DeMent's.
So for that, we have created a four focus algorithm that's move to more and more complex.